how's it going guys this is Chris aady
again with another video and today we
actually have something a bit different
so insert gadgets was kind enough to
give us this axon I don't know how it's
pronounced don't blame me on how I'm
pronouncing it soon I don't know but
it's the t3a it's the soldering station
as you guys can see right here um I did
turn it on just wanted to make sure that
it's good try to connect it as fast as I
can
I wanna just do like a quick review on
this compared to my hako station
um it would have been a better
comparison with my other JBC station
however it's on my other desk and my
other desk is occupied at the moment so
I'm just gonna give a quick comparison
between the
I soon and the hako fm203
there's a marginally big difference in
the price so like let's see for example
right here I'm on the injured gadgets
website right so
the recommended product on this let's
type in the model name
they also have a partnership with JC it
seems like it came in with the with a
gift of um JC drawing it looks like it
might be
I don't know what that is I'll check it
out it might be a subscription or
something but
so there's two models of this this the
t3a and the t3b the t3b is a bit better
it looks like it's the newer design
um this where um the iron holder is a
bit better this is kind of a little
wonky it doesn't have like a
the the the copper braids that you could
use to clean the tip
however this costs the t3a costs 153.21
on injured gadgets and the Axiom 3B t3b
it costs 169 this is the one I would
recommend you guys use it looks like
it's the same head unit the only
difference would be the
the iron holder it seems a bit sturdy
you can you have space where you can put
the tips if you have space where you can
disconnect the tips and you have the
braids right there where you can
actually clean the head of the tip so
um they gave us the t3a to review we're
gonna do the review on this however
um there's virtually no difference
between the head unit itself and the
iron it's the same iron as the t3b so
this comparison is also viable for the
t3b now without further Ado we're gonna
go ahead and
first um we're gonna do like a
solder test between tips to see how fast
we want to see how fast it gets hot
right now it's in standby they're both
on sleep as you guys can see I'm not
going to use the micro pencil I am going
to use the big tip on the hako
um they're both at sleep right now I
want to see how fast they get hot how
steady it is
um to melt solder how steady it is to
Wick an iPhone XS Max board that we are
currently working on
and um we will also demonstrate whether
we can remove like a capacitor resistor
how how easy it is to remove a capacitor
or resistor using the
iron instead of hot air so let's go
ahead and give that a shot so first
things first I want to go ahead and grab
the p3a you guys can see it's getting
pretty warm fast it's set as 350.
so it did look like it got hot at 400
and now it's regulating back to 350. it
does have three channels as you guys can
see they're from factory set at 280 350
and 380 you can adjust that in settings
I want to show the comparison first then
we can go ahead and show you the
different settings that it has
um you can also see right here it does
show the ambient temperature which is 23
degrees Celsius
so let's go ahead now let's just clean
up the tip because I tried to use it
first
alrighty now let's go ahead and check
how easy it melts to solder
which is pretty steady honestly and it
the tips are pretty
decent as you guys can see
it is warm it is warm enough at 350 it's
plenty of temperature
it doesn't hesitate at all to melt this
type of wire let's go ahead and try our
hako in comparison so for example the
hako let's see how fast it warms up let
me just untangle The Wire
so the hako is set in Fahrenheit so it
is at 755 right which should be almost
equivalent I have a different bigger tip
on this however let's go ahead and
in comparison they're almost the same
they melt at the same speed and
everything which is very expectable
so it's very well it's expected I would
want to say no
also another reason why I didn't want to
go through
first telling you about the tips and the
Machine it's because what actually
matters is how reliable it is doing
day-to-day soldering jobs instead of
like oh wow it has a fancy it has a
fancy tip it has it uses JVC tips oh my
God it has different settings it's not
really what matters no matter what
matters is how reliable it is so um we
have a good week
that we're gonna use to
disorder this uh interposer so first
we're gonna do it with this
um the reason why I don't have a chisel
tip on the other one is because I don't
really like using the Chisel tip much I
like to use the this type that I showed
you guys on my Hackle but let's go ahead
just make sure it's warm enough
it does get warm pretty fast it does get
back to temperature pretty quick so
so let's go ahead uh it is wicking it
pretty decent
let's try to go a little bit fast to see
the temperature wise
that's pretty good actually that's not
bad
so as you guys can see it's pretty
steady it does work pretty nice
let's clean up the tip
I definitely recommend again getting if
you guys would want to get this after
this review I would definitely recommend
getting the 3B because it does come with
the tip cleaner better than this
um
let's go ahead and cut that
let's try with the hako
okay now we're gonna do this side with
the hako
so this is a kind of a different tip
it's expected that this tip would
probably get a bit more hotter than the
other one but however this tip is big
enough to do micro soldering jobs so it
should be good enough for wicking could
be you know good enough to do any any
soldering work on any iPhone board so
let's go ahead and use this tip
so as you guys can see they are pretty
steady
as far as um temperature wise and
wicking capabilities
let's go fast on this stretch so you can
show you guys warm-up tip all right nice
there you go
so as you guys can see they are pretty
steady with the temperature
I did
um this tip is obviously has a smaller
diameter than the Chisel tip
temperature wise working is very decent
now what matters is can you remove a
resistor with this machine right so the
resistors they obviously um well big
capacitors like on MacBook boards and
such
they tend to suck up a bit of heat so
um let me just get hold real quick
all right
so we have here it's a Macbook board
from a
looks like it's a 1706 or something
similar I believe 1706.
let me check the model number
zero zero eight five zero
yeah it's a 1706 because it has CD 3215s
all right so let's go ahead and do
something right so what we're going to
do is we're going to grab our flux and
then we're gonna try to remove
um I'm gonna find a decent size
capacitor that can handle
let me see the diameter of this tip yeah
so
let me go ahead and try to Showcase it
on
this capacitor right here
okay
so we have two capacitors right next to
each other
I'm gonna use I'm gonna remove one with
the t3a and I'm gonna remove the second
with the hako and I want to do a
comparison as far as like how easy it is
let me try to see if I can get my chisel
tip just so I can make it a better
comparison
let me get my sugar too
all right
oh this single tip has seen better days
um
no it's okay I'll let me see this one
yeah all right this one is the same size
almost let's do a comparison real quick
so it's almost the same size this is a
bit finer I would say but we will see
how good it is and how effective let's
just change the tip on our
um
Taco real quick
don't mind the loud beat
[Music]
let's put this on the side
all right clean this Step Up all right
so
let's go ahead and try to remove
this capacitor right here right so now
we filled up with uh flux let's go ahead
clean up the tip again
add solder to the tip
just you have a good enough blob it is
starting to get dark because it looks
like the tip is still running hot let's
clean it up again
we don't want to use it when the flux on
there is burning already
all right let's try again
all right grab our tweezers
let's go ahead and see how reliable it
is to remove this capacitor
so I can see it move
there you go so I mean it wasn't bad
removing it with a big solder blob
it did stay hot it did stay consistent
um I'm not sure if the video would have
showcased the the power right there I
didn't really pay attention I was
actually looking there I'm not sure if
we had grabbed it did we grab it
video
we will we will check again we will
double check
um
let's go ahead and do it with the hako
now
put a bit more flux
foreign
ER
I gotta find a better setup for my hako
um
also there's a big size difference
between both however the Haku does have
two tips advantage
okay compared to the hakua the Haku
removed it
very easily
that came out straight
um that could be due to the
um tip size obviously this is a fatter
tip this is a bigger tip we are using it
on a on a on a big board however this
did not hesitate to remove this
capacitor so
um let's go ahead and check again on
another similar capacitor right here
just to see
um how
how much power it consumes if you guys
can see the percentage right here
how how much power it uses to
um actually get that removed so
let's go ahead and showcase that put
flux
put solder on the tip clean the tip
pretty well
okay
nice decent solder blob on there
so let's go ahead and check you guys can
see the power
oh it actually removed this one pretty
fast and it only used up to 15 power
which is actually kind of really good
really impressive
um so far I really like the tip
um holding it wise it does it is a bit
thinner than nihako obviously if you
guys you guys can obviously look at the
diameter it's it's thinner
um tip to tip to base ratio it's almost
similar if you want to say it's pretty
good obviously it is a bit shorter a pen
so if you kind of compare it with the
base right there
it is a bit shorter obviously
um it is a thinner tip it is a thinner
base
they use
JBC tips they use the c245
as you guys can see from with the box it
comes with three tips you have the
Chisel tip you have the um
conical
this is the conical yeah you guys can
see right there and in there you have
the straight one
and they're pretty thin there they
should be all the tips you need honestly
to do
um to do uh board repair on an iPhone
this is pretty thin enough this is
pretty decent this is very this is small
enough for where you can Wick
um you might also want to get a finer
tip if you want to do like smaller
jumpers but I'm pretty sure you can get
those from inter gadgets website I'll
link it in the in the description of
this video is going to go on YouTube
it's going to go on Facebook
um
so other than that it's pretty good now
let's go ahead and show you guys some of
the settings
um before I go into settings I want to
say I really like this tip it's pretty
decent I am actually surprised at the
temperature consistency
to where it like it was able to remove a
big capacitor without hesitating if you
try that with a JBC the smaller tips
with the with the Nano station it's
gonna hesitate it's gonna choke a bit it
will still remove it but it would
require a bit more power because you
guys can see this is only needed 15
power right there it only needed 15
power to remove this capacitor which was
pretty impressive in my opinion
um
let's go ahead and dive into settings of
this machine right here so let's go
ahead and
show you guys know so right now it's
actually cooling because it's in the
base right so let's click set and this
is the settings now first things first
when you first receive it is going to be
in Chinese so this knob I don't really
like it much because like it takes two
clicks to move
um to move uh
whatever you want to call a unit or
whatever so like click two it moves
click two I don't like it I wanna I want
each click to move a setting but first
it comes in Chinese right so it's gonna
look like this you click set you go down
to English click English and now it's in
English so you can set up Max temp which
I think is pretty cool it doesn't get it
won't get hotter than that
so um
sorry
so you don't click this set you click
this knob right there to enter so max
temp is set as 500 you obviously do not
want to go to 500 you wanna set it up at
lower but we'll we'll go ahead and play
with that later you can lock the
temperature it would remain the same
temperature if you want
it'll be on off
dormancy I'm assuming like if when it
goes to sleep
you can um
you can put a sleep timer you can put a
stat by mode temperature dormancy temp
um
basically what temperature you want the
tip to to sleep at
um
delay if you want it after you put it in
there if you want it to go to sleep
immediately or you want it to wait a few
seconds
dormancy show I don't know why she says
it is Chinese off
on
anyway basically it will show that if
it's sleeping or not sleep timer if you
it would go to sleep automatically
standby mode
no let's go ahead back now you have
sound you can get rid of the Annoying
beep as you guys can see it doesn't beep
anymore
temp level
um these are for the channels you have
three channels you have 280 you have 350
you have 380 these comes default you can
change whichever temperature you want
um I believe 350 is perfect for any
almost any application you need 280
would be ideal if you want to do small
jumpers on like uh if you're fixing a
home button for example I would say you
can use 280 280 is very convenient it
doesn't burn the flex cable doesn't burn
the flux too fast
and um it won't damage the wire you can
reset it temperature unit if you're
accustomed to Celsius like me you can
keep it to Celsius
you want to switch it to Fahrenheit you
can however Celsius is the way to go in
my opinion
also System Info basically it tells you
that this is the t3a the software
version hardware version blah blah blah
so let's go ahead and um
look at the back of this unit right so
the back of this unit
as you guys can see
on off button it has an output DC of 24
volts you have this is a ground that I
have attached to the table and you have
this is for the Sleep sensor for The
Cutting one moment I'll grab with you
this is the on and off button and there
you guys have it my opinion is I
really recommend this station it is
pretty decent it is pretty sturdy it
does save you space and it should be
able to handle any job you throw at it
pretty much
thank you guys for watching this video
and as always have a good day
thank you